<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Marco Gomiero</title>
    <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Marco Gomiero</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shellporter</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/shellporter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/shellporter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shellporter is a macOS menu bar utility that opens a terminal in the project directory of the active IDE window with a single global hotkey or a click from the menu bar. It requires macOS 14 or later and Accessibility permission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supported IDEs include JetBrains (IntelliJ, Android Studio, Fleet), VS Code, Cursor, Xcode, and Antigravity. Supported terminals include Terminal.app, iTerm2, Ghostty, Kitty, and a custom command option. Hotkeys and terminal are configurable in Settings. A second hotkey copies the project path to the clipboard. The app runs entirely on the machine; no network calls, telemetry, or analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReaderFlow</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/readerflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/readerflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ReaderFlow is a clean, privacy-focused read-it-later app that works completely offline. Articles can be saved and synced across devices with Dropbox (Android, iOS and macOS) or iCloud (iOS and macOS), for distraction-free reading anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content is processed and stored locally on the device with on-device parsing,no server in the middle. Migration from Pocket, Instapaper, Omnivore or custom CSV exports is supported. Articles can be tagged and archived; the same experience is available on Android, iOS and macOS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeedFlow</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/feed-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/feed-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FeedFlow is a minimal, uncluttered RSS reader available on Android, iOS, macOS, Windows and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Minimalist design to keep the focus on what matters; seamless sync across devices with iCloud (iOS/macOS), Dropbox or Google Drive; FreshRSS, Miniflux, Feedbin and BazQux integration; flexible reading with reader mode or a preferred browser.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FeedFlow is built with Jetpack Compose, Compose Multiplatform, and SwiftUI, with shared logic via Kotlin Multiplatform, and uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/prof18/RSS-Parser&#34;&gt;RSSParser&lt;/a&gt;, a multiplatform RSS parsing library I built.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spoton</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/spoton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/spoton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoton is a WearOS application that simplifies mobile hotspot management by allowing users to control their phone&amp;rsquo;s hotspot directly from their smartwatch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app consists of two components:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A WearOS app that provides a simple interface to toggle the hotspot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A companion Android phone app that handles the background communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Spoton, users can enable or disable their phone&amp;rsquo;s mobile hotspot with a single tap on their watch, eliminating the need to take out and unlock their phone. This is particularly useful when frequently switching the hotspot on and off for connecting laptops, tablets, or other devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KMP Framework Bundler</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/kmp-framework-bundler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/kmp-framework-bundler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Gradle plugin for Kotlin Multiplatform projects that generate a XCFramework for Apple targets or a FatFramework for iOS targets, and manages the publishing process in a CocoaPod Repository.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plugin is uploaded on MavenCentral.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoneyFlow</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/money-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/money-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MoneyFlow is a Kotlin Multiplatform personal finance app targeting Android and iOS with Compose Multiplatform. The app is in the middle of a rewrite with an updated architecture to better support Compose Multiplatform and keep the Android and iOS shells thin; the shared module is the source of truth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Planned and in-progress features include transaction entry and list, edit transaction, custom categories, recap screen with plots, budgeting, CSV import and export, currency selection, and lock view with biometrics. Progress can be tracked on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/prof18/MoneyFlow&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QR Reader Secure</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/qr-reader-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/qr-reader-secure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;QR Reader Secure is a simple QR Reader designed and developed with a focus on privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to develop it after a failed search for a simple and secure reader for my parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app is very simple (the aim is to scan a code and open the link, only this!) and it does not require sneaky, strange and useless permissions just for the sake of stealing your data. There aren&amp;rsquo;t ads, trackers of any sort and what do you scan remains on your phone. The only requested permission is for the camera.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friends Tournament</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/friends-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/friends-tournament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mobile application to manage and create tournaments. Friends Tournament will help to generate videogames tournament, sports tournament, board games tournament, whatever type of tournament. All you need to do is to provide the number of players, the number of matches, and the number of players that can play at the same time. That&amp;rsquo;s all! Friends Tournament will then generate the matches and the rounds for you. Then you can keep track of the players&amp;rsquo; score and a nice leaderboard is automatically generated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSS Parser</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/rss-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/rss-parser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RSS Parser is a Kotlin Multiplatform library for parsing RSS, Atom and RDF feeds. It supports Android, JVM, iOS, macOS, tvOS, watchOS, wasmJS and JS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The library can fetch and parse feeds from a URL or from an XML string. It is published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://central.sonatype.com/artifact/com.prof18.rssparser/rssparser&#34;&gt;Maven Central&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedflow.dev&#34;&gt;FeedFlow&lt;/a&gt; uses it for multiplatform RSS parsing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Parser</title>
      <link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/youtube-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/projects/youtube-parser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Android library to get video&amp;rsquo;s information from Youtube channels. You can retrieve title, link and thumbnails of a video from a specific channel. For each video you can also get statistics like views, number of like, dislike, favorite and comments. The library is uploaded on MavenCentral.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
