<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Marco Gomiero</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/</link><description>Software Engineer · Google Developer Expert for Kotlin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 17:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marcogomiero.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-jobs-quartz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-jobs-quartz/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5: Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor Sometimes, on a backend project, there is the need to run one or more tasks periodically, like for system administration, maintenance, backup, syncing content in the background, etc.</description></item><item><title>Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-setup-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-setup-documentation/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5: Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor When a backend project exposes some APIs, there should also be a place where the clients of those APIs can see and understand what can be consumed.</description></item><item><title>How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-migration-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2022/ktor-migration-liquibase/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5 Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor Databases are an important and critical part of backend infrastructures.</description></item><item><title>How to fix the "Unable to locate a Java Runtime" error on Xcode with Kotlin Multiplatform</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/kmp-no-java-runtime-error-xcode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/kmp-no-java-runtime-error-xcode/</guid><description>A couple of days ago I opened my Kotlin Multiplatform pet project MoneyFlow on a different machine than usual. When I tried to run the app on the iOS simulator on Xcode, the build failed with a very strange error: &amp;ldquo;The operation couldn&amp;rsquo;t be completed. Unable to locate a Java Runtime&amp;rdquo;.
This was a very strange issue because the JDK is installed and everything is working on the command line and Android Studio/IntelliJ.</description></item><item><title>How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-in-memory-db-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-in-memory-db-testing/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5 Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor Usually, in a backend project, there are different instances of the same database: one for production (or more than one, it depends on the architecture), one for staging, and a local one that runs in the development machine.</description></item><item><title>Building an XCFramework on Kotlin Multiplatform from Kotlin 1.5.30</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/kmp-xcframework-official-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/kmp-xcframework-official-support/</guid><description>A few days ago, Kotlin 1.5.30 has been released. One of the features contained in the release is the official support for XCFrameworks on Kotlin Multiplatform.
XCFramework is a binary that can contain multiple platform-specific variants (even for iOS and macOS at the same time). It has been introduced by Apple during the WWDC 2019 as a replacement for FatFrameworks.
Before Kotlin 1.5.30, an XCFramework could be created only by running the xcrun command that will pack the frameworks for every different required platform into an XCFramework.</description></item><item><title>How to build an XCFramework on Kotlin Multiplatform</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/build-xcframework-kmp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/build-xcframework-kmp/</guid><description>When you start integrating Kotlin Multiplatform (I’ll call it KMP in the rest of the article) in an existing project you most likely don’t have a mono-repo structure (and making a refactor to achieve this kind of architecture will not be easy). An example of architecture is the following, with a repository for every platform.
To understand how to integrate KMP into existing code, give a look at my previous article: “Introducing Kotlin Multiplatform in an existing project”</description></item><item><title>Connect to Open VPN during Gitlab Pipeline</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/gitlab-pipeline-vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/gitlab-pipeline-vpn/</guid><description>Gitlab CI/CD offers the possibility to create a pipeline, which runs when something changes in the repository. A pipeline consists of one or more stages that run in order and in these stages, for example, it is possible to build the project, run the tests, create the artifacts, etc. For more information about Gitlab CI/CD, I suggest you look over the documentation.
These out-of-the-box solutions really simplify the work to be done to have a CI up and running.</description></item><item><title>How to persist Ktor logs</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-logging-on-disk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-logging-on-disk/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5 Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor Logs are a vital part of software development.</description></item><item><title>Structuring a Ktor project</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-project-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/ktor-project-structure/</guid><description>SERIES: Building a backend with Ktor Part 1: Structuring a Ktor project Part 2: How to persist Ktor logs Part 3: How to use an in-memory database for testing on Ktor Part 4: How to handle database migrations with Liquibase on Ktor Part 5 Generate API documentation from Swagger on Ktor Part 6: How to schedule jobs with Quartz on Ktor It’s been a few months since I’ve started working with Ktor to build the backend of Revelop.</description></item></channel></rss>