<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android on Marco Gomiero</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in Android on Marco Gomiero</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marcogomiero.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating old artifacts from JCenter to MavenCentral</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/move-libray-jcenter-to-maven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2021/move-libray-jcenter-to-maven/</guid><description>As you may have heard, JCenter is shutting down in May 2021.
Into the Sunset on May 1st: Bintray, JCenter, GoCenter, and ChartCenter
https://jfrog.com/blog/into-the-sunset-bintray-jcenter-gocenter-and-chartcenter/
So, if you are using JCenter as the repository for your libraries (as me), it’s time to migrate.
In this article, I will not go through the publishing process of a library to MavenCentral, because there are already plenty of resources available. For example, I followed the one written by Márton Braun.</description></item><item><title>How to publish and distribute your Android library</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2019/publish-librery-android/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2019/publish-librery-android/</guid><description>Update - February 2021 As you may have heard, JCenter is shutting down in May 2021.
Into the Sunset on May 1st: Bintray, JCenter, GoCenter, and ChartCenter
https://jfrog.com/blog/into-the-sunset-bintray-jcenter-gocenter-and-chartcenter/
So, this tutorial is no longer recommended because it explains how to publish an Android library to JCenter.
I suggested you follow this guide written by Márton Braun.
Publishing Android libraries to MavenCentral in 2021 https://getstream.io/blog/publishing-libraries-to-mavencentral-2021/
If you have already published a library on JCenter and you want to migrate the old artifacts to MavenCentral, you can follow the guide that I’ve written:</description></item><item><title>A journey from Async Task to Kotlin Coroutines</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2019/asynctask-to-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2019/asynctask-to-coroutines/</guid><description>Photo by felipe lopez on Unsplash
Some weeks ago I released a new version of the RSS Parser Library and I talked about the update in a blog post.
RSS Parser 2.0: bye bye Async Task, welcome Coroutines This update brought a huge change in the infrastructure of the library. SPOILER: Kotlin and coroutines. Today, in this post I want to talk about the transition process and all the decisions that I have made to develop this new version.</description></item><item><title>RSS Parser 2.0: bye bye Async Task, welcome Coroutines</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2018/bye-async-task/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2018/bye-async-task/</guid><description>Finally, I found some time to sit down and work on my library RSS Parser. Before starting to describe all the cool stuff that I’ve introduced with this update, I want to thank you all for the support. In fact this year, the library exceeded 100 stars on Github, that seems a little goal but it means a lot to me.
I wrote this library back in 2016 and now in 2018, the code was “ugly” compared to all the coolest stuff provided by Kotlin.</description></item><item><title>New update for RSS Parser: featured image</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2018/image-update-rss-lib/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2018/image-update-rss-lib/</guid><description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve released a new version of the Android library RSS-Parser
This library allows you to easily download an (or multiple) RSS Feed in order to display it in your application. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know RSS-Parser, you can give a look to the blog post dedicated to it. In that post I&amp;rsquo;ll give also some tip about the library usage.
Thanks to the issues and the suggestions provided by the community, I&amp;rsquo;ve improved the parsing of the feature image of the article.</description></item><item><title>New update for RSS Parser: article categories</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/update-rss-lib/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/update-rss-lib/</guid><description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve released a new version of the Android library RSS-Parser
This library allows you to easily download an (or multiple) RSS Feed in order to display it in your application. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know RSS-Parser, you can give a look to the blog post dedicated to it. In that post I&amp;rsquo;ll give also some tip about the library usage.
Starting from today you can get also the categories of the article, like shown in the screen below.</description></item><item><title>How to easily handle RSS Feeds on Android with RSS Parser</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/rss-parser-library/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/rss-parser-library/</guid><description>Two month ago I have talked about YoutubeParser, an Android Library that I developed. Today I want to talk about RSS-Parser, another library that I wrote.
This library allows you to easily download an (or multiple) RSS Feed in order to display it in your application. For every article it is possible to download the following information:
Title Author Description Content Main Image Link Publication Date Here you can find an example of feed.</description></item><item><title>New big update for Youtube Parser: video stats and much more</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/update-yt-parser-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/update-yt-parser-2/</guid><description>Finally I&amp;rsquo;ve released a new big update for YoutubeParser. For people who don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, don&amp;rsquo;t worry now I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain all.
YoutubeParser is the first Android library that I ever wrote. With this library it is possible to get information of videos from Youtube channels. These information are:
Title Link Thumbnail, with three different image size. After a year I&amp;rsquo;ve released this new big update, named 2.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with backup &amp; restore on Android (Slide &amp; Video)</title><link>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/backup-restore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcogomiero.com/posts/2017/backup-restore/</guid><description>I know, I&amp;rsquo;m very very late.
On 17th December 2016 I&amp;rsquo;ve attended my first talk as speaker (GDG Venezia Tech Talks 17/12/16). Despite the firsts scared thoughts this was an amazing experience! In fact I&amp;rsquo;ve replicated that, but I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about it with a future post (that won&amp;rsquo;t be published the next year - I promise :) ). The topic of the talk was a hot one: backup and restore on Android Application.</description></item></channel></rss>